Guide to the Elizabeth Willis DeHuff Collection of American Indian Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Artworks, 1917-1945; Series I; 7.6; (14 boxes)
  - 20.5" x 17.5" Boxes
    - Moquino, Juanito. [Forest scene with deer and squirrel]. #106, 1930; Watercolor on paperboard; 14.5 x 11 inches (Box 12, Folder 138)
      On verso: "Given to me by B. J. D. [Nordfelt?] -1941 / printed about 1930."
    - Po-Povi Da. [Clown on donkey holding a hen]. #198, 1939; Gouache on paperboard; 16.5 x 14.5 inches (Box 12, Folder 139)
      On verso: "Antonio Martinez, son of Julian Martinez (& Maria Montoya). 1939"
    - Pop Chalee. [Deer in forest]. #83, Undated; Gouache on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Tewe'kwe. "Sword swallowers." #146, 1920; Gouache and pencil on paper; 15 x 11 inches (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - [?], Earnest. "Hilili." #54, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 142)
      On verso: signed note by John D. DeHuff, dated Jan 28, 1940
    - [?], Earnest. "-J" #55, [circa 1917]; Pencil, crayon and watercolor on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - [?], Earnest. "Ku." #56, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - [?], Earnest. "Hoo." #57, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 145)
    - [?], Earnest. "[Soyohim?]." #58, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 146)
    - [?], Earnest. "[Soyohim?]." #59, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 12, Folder 147)
    - [?], James. "Hilili (He'le le)." #69, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 13, Folder 148)
    - [?], James. "Skelilii." #70, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 13, Folder 149)
    - [?], James. "Hilili." #71, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 13, Folder 150)
      On verso: signed note by John D. DeHuff dated Jan 28, 1940
    - [?], James. "Hu." #72, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 13, Folder 151)
    - [?], James. [Kachina raising sticks]. # 73, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - [?], James. "Wa'käsi (cow)." # 74, [circa 1917]; Pencil and crayon on paper; 11.5 x 8 inches (Box 13, Folder 153)
      On verso: signed note by John D. DeHuff dated Jan 28, 1940.
    - Unidentified. "Salymobier." #31, 1920; Watercolor and ink on paper; 11 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 154)
      On verso: "These are the whippers that whip the children when they are initiated into the Koko fraternity. When they have been whipped then they can dance in any dances. 1920"
    - Unidentified. "Kayemshi." #80, 1920; Pencil and watercolor on paper; 15 x 11 inches (Box 13, Folder 155)
      On verso: "For short mud head. He is one the fun makers for the dances. There are few of them and each one represents a clan. They are supposed to be children of brothers and sisters hence are idiots and do all sorts of crazy stunts."
    - Unidentified. [Green and Black Kachina]. On verso: [Kachina running from dark cloud with rattle]. #6 & #7, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 13, Folder 156)
    - Unidentified. "Ah-nate Katchina (Long Hair)." On verso: "Bird maiden." #10 & #11, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 13, Folder 157)
    - Unidentified. "Ko-Ko-purl-mana / Insect fly - dragonfly." On verso: "Hoo-lulu (Sound he makes gives name)." #12 & #13, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 13, Folder 158)
    - Unidentified. [Kachina carrying bow with evergreens]. On verso: "Coo-yen-tsi." #14 & #15, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 13, Folder 159)
    - Unidentified. [Four Kachinas chasing a man]. On verso: [Kachina with blue embroidered kilt]. #16 & #17, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 13, Folder 160)
    - Unidentified. [Woman speaking with Kachina]. #18, Undated; Pencil on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 13, Folder 161)
    - Unidentified. [Two Kachinas, one with green bushel]. On verso: [Ball game overseen by figure]. #21 & #22, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 13, Folder 162)
    - Unidentified. [Kachina pointing finger]. On verso: [Man chasing Kachina and clown teasing man]. #23 & #24, Undated; Pencil and crayon on paper; 12 x 9 inches (Box 13, Folder 163)
    - Unidentified. "Sketch of [two red] mudhead figures]. #30, Undated; Watercolor and ink on paper; 11 x 14 inches (Box 13, Folder 164)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo couples dance]. #150, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 11.25 x 13 inches (Box 13, Folder 165)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo woman feeding dogs]. #151, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 12 inches (Box 14, Folder 166)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo man picking plants accompanied by black horse]. #152, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 12 inches (Box 14, Folder 167)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo men and women seated indoors]. #153, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 11.25 x 13 inches (Box 14, Folder 168)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo men seated indoors with shoes]. #154, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 11.25 x 13 inches (Box 14, Folder 169)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo women cooking]. #155, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 11 x 14 inches (Box 14, Folder 170)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo family eating under awning]. #156, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 11.25 x 13 inches (Box 14, Folder 171)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo men chasing after woman]. # 157, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 13 x 11 inches (Box 14, Folder 172)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo women playing game with stones]. #158, Undated; Gouache on paperboard; 13 x 11 inches (Box 14, Folder 173)
    - Unidentified. [Five Indian religious figures]. #159, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 11 x 13 inches (Box 14, Folder 174)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo woman washing man's hair]. #160, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 10 x 11 inches (Box 14, Folder 175)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo group sleeping inside]. # 161, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 10 x 13 inches (Box 14, Folder 176)
    - Unidentified.[Navajo woman hitching horses to a wagon]. # 162, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 10.5 x 13 inches (Box 14, Folder 177)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo sheep farm]. #163, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 13 x 12 inches (Box 14, Folder 178)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo feast]. #189, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 12.5 x 18 inches (Box 14, Folder 179)
    - Unidentified. [Navajo wagon train camped]. #190, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 12 x 17 inches (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - 22.75" x 28.75" Box
    - Calabaza, Gonzalio. "Shalako figures are about 10 ft. or 12 ft. tall and are carried and manipulated. Their beaks can snap open and shut." #192, 1923; Gouache on paperboard; 19.5 x 8 inches (Box 15, Folder 181)
      On verso: "Gonzalio Calabaza, painter, 6th grade by 1923. Santa Fe, New Mexico / Property of J. D. Dehuff, Government Indian School, Santa Fe, N. M."
    - Calabaza, Gonzalio. "Warriors dancing the War Dance." #193, 1923; Watercolor on paperboard; 13 x 23 inches (Box 15, Folder 182)
      On verso, in ink: "Property of Gonzalio Calabaza, a boy from Santo Domingo Pueblo." In pencil: "Pardon the soiled condition. He had the picture pinned up in his dormitory room."
    - Herrera, Velino Shije (Ma Pe Wi). [Two hands destroying, one with lightining and one with a cannon].#194, Undated; Ink on paperboard; 22 x 14 inches (Box 15, Folder 183)
    - Martinez, Miguel (Wich-[cheerg?]-ka-ri). "Ah-van-yohs." #197, 1923; Watercolor on paperboard; 12 x 20 inches (Box 15, Folder 184)
      On verso: "The copy of a painting from the kiva wall. These two water snakes called "Ah-van-yohs" bring the rains. They lash up clouds out of the bodies of water with their tails and make rain fall from those clouds with their lightning tongues. The center design is all symbolic of the world and fertility."
    - Unidentified. "Illustration for Katchinas in Holland's Magazine." #191, 1926; Gouache and ink on paperboard; 19 x 13.5 inches (Box 15, Folder 185)
    - Unidentified. "Katchinas for August." #188, Undated; Watercolor and ink on paperboard; 19 x 13.5 inches (Box 15, Folder 186)
      Annotated in pencil.